<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="schema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<doc>
    <header>
        <docTitle>Letter from Irvin Kochel to Mary Behrend</docTitle>
        <docAuthor><persName pers = "#IHK">Irvin Kochel</persName></docAuthor>
        <docType>Letter</docType>
        <docDate when="1958-10-04">April 10, 1958</docDate>
        <listImages>
            <image href="irvin_kochel_04-10-58_page1.PNG"/>
            <image href="irvin_kochel_04-10-58_page2.PNG"/>
        </listImages>
    </header>
    <body>

            <docHead><date when="1958-04-10">April 10, 1958</date></docHead>

            <recipient><persName pers="#MB">Mrs. Mary B. Behrend</persName>
                <address><addLine type="street">21 West Putnam</addLine>
                    <addLine type="City State">Greenwich Conn.</addLine></address> 
            </recipient>
        <p n="1">Dear <persName pers="#MB">Mrs. Behrend</persName>: I hope you will forgive my tardiness in replying o your most recent communica- tion. I very much enjoyed the card you sent from <location type="state">Hawaii</location>, particularly since it arrived during a long snowy winter in <location type="city">Erie</location>. It was wonderful to view the surf and sunshine indicated in the picture. It gave me real hope that <time type="month">Spring</time> and <time type="season">Summer</time> would eventually arrive.</p>
            <p n="2">We have all been very busy here at <location>Behrend Center</location> working on some long range plans for development and growth, which I know when completed you will be very much interested in seeing. The picture is very encouraging when we view it over a ten year period. Considering the growth in population in the <location type="city">Erie</location> area and the increased birth rate, we have good reason to believe that the next ten years may show an increase in our student body to as many as a thousand students. This growth is predicated on the hope that we will be able to build several dormitories on the <name type="location">Behrend campus</name>.</p>
            <p n="3">You will be interested to know that the University is planning to build a sewage disposal plant, financed by University funds. This plant is a necessity to us if we are going to prepare for future growth. We do not plan to spend any of <persName pers="#Unknown">Dr. Otto Behrend</persName>'s bequest for maintenance but rather would hope to use it for the construction of new classrooms and laboratory facilities. I know that the Uni- versity will respect the wishes of our local Advisory Board and they certainly are very much in favor of utilizing this money for expansion purposes rather than maintenance.</p>
            <p n="4">We have at the present time 223 students enrolled and a very encouraging note may be found in the fact that we have as of this date received admissions for 2/3 of the Freshman class as compared to last year's entering Freshman class. Me have had beautiful weather in <location type="city">Erie</location> the past few weeks and the students are get- ting eager to clean out the <location type="object">swimming pool</location> and prepare it for use before they leave for their <time type="season">summer vacation</time>. Actually, there are only six more weeks of school re- maining before the end of May when t he students ill be leaving for their <time type="season">summer vacation</time>.</p>
            <p n="5">I had a very nice note from <persName pers ="#Unknown">Miss Wild</persName> and <persName pers="#Unknown">Mrs. Sayre</persName>, indicating that they plan to be in <location type="city">Erie</location> in <time type="season">June</time> to play in a golf tournament. I expect this is probably the women's western open golf tournament to be held at the <name type="org">Kahka Club</name>
                <time type="month day">June 19-20-21</time>, I am looking forvard to seeing them at that time. <persName pers = "#Unknown">Mrs. Sayre</persName> also indicated she planned to bring her sons along on this trip and am very anxious to meet them.</p>
        
            <p n="6"><persName pers = "#Unknown">Mrs. Kochel</persName> and the children are all well, although during <time type="month">March</time> we had a case of measles which vas contracted by all three children. <persName pers = "#Unknown">Jeffrey</persName>, our oldest song is in third grade now and getting to be quite a young man. <persName pers = "#Unknown">Patty</persName> has been going to kindergarten this year and <persName pers="#Unknown">Irvin, the III</persName>, our youngest who is now 4 years old, is of course still at home and growing like a weed.</p>
            <p n="7"><persName pers="#Unknown">Mrs. Kochel</persName> is planning to have a tea for the women students at the College sometime in <time type="month">May</time>. If time permits and it is convenient, I do hope you will visit us,</p>
       <closing>Cordially yours, IHK: HA P. S.</closing>

               <p n="8">Enclosed are some clippings you may be interested in.</p>
    </body>

</doc>
